Hankook Lee

PH.D STUDENT @ ALIN LAB IN KAIST

KAIST N1-917, 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, South Korea

■ hankook.lee@kaist.ac.kr | ♠ hankook.github.io | ᡚ hankook | ▶ Hankook Lee

Research Interests

My research goal is to develop efficient and scalable deep learning algorithms that require few or no human annotation, and ultimately apply them to real-world applications with massive data. More specifically, my research interests lie in neural architectures, data augmentations, transfer/few-shot learning and un/self-supervised learning in various domains such as vision, chemistry, and tabular data.

Education

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Sep. 2018 - Present

Advisor: linwoo Shin

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

· Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2018

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)B.Sc. in Mathematics and Computer Science (Double major)

Daejeon, South Korea Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

• GPA: 3.93/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

Publications

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, *: Equal contribution

[C7/W] Improving Transferability of Representations via Augmentation-Aware Self-Supervision

Online

Hankook Lee, Kibok Lee, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Dec. 2021

- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- · International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021 Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception

[C6] Self-Improved Retrosynthetic Planning

Online

Junsu Kim, Sungsoo Ahn, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2021

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021

[C5/W] RetCL: A Selection-based Approach for Retrosynthesis via Contrastive Learning

Online

Hankook Lee, Sungsoo Ahn, Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, Eunho Yang, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Aug. 2021

- International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021
- NeurIPS Workshop for Machine Learning for Molecules, 2020

[C4] GTA: Graph Truncated Attention for Retrosynthesis

Online

Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, June Yong Yang, Seohui Bae, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin, Sung Ju Hwang, Eunho Yang

Feb. 2021

• AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

[C3] Guiding Deep Molecular Optimization with Genetic Exploration

Online

Sungsoo Ahn, Junsu Kim, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

Dec. 2020

[C2] Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations

Online

Hankook Lee, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

JUI. 2020

- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020
- Received Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (2019)

[C1] Learning What and Where to Transfer

Long Beach, CA, USA

Yunhun Jang*, **Hankook Lee***, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2019

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2019

[P] Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically

Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin

• arXiv preprint

Work Experience_

SAIT (Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology)

Visiting student

• Developed ML-based retrosynthesis algorithms (AAAI 2021, IJCAI 2021 papers).

Suwon, South Korea Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

FrogramsSeoul, South KoreaResearch and Development EngineerAug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

• Built an automatic movie tagging system using movies' news/reviews based on Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).

- Built a Scala-based movie rating prediction system based on non-negative matrix factorization.
- The incorporation name was changed to Watcha Inc. at 2018.

Honors & Awards _____

| 2019 | Winner, Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (ICML 2020 paper) | Daejeon, South Korea |
|------|--|------------------------|
| 2019 | Travel award, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019 | Long Beach, CA, USA |
| 2013 | Finalist, International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) World Finals | St. Petersburg, Russia |
| 2012 | 1st Place (Grand Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional | Daejeon, South Korea |
| 2010 | 2nd Place (Gold Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional | Daejeon, South Korea |
| 2009 | Gold Prize, Problem Solving Division, Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI) | Seoul, South Korea |

Services_____

2022 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2022

2021 **Conference Reviewer**, ICLR 2021, ICML 2021, NeurIPS 2021

2020 **Conference Reviewer,** ICLR 2020, NeruIPS 2020

2020 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2020

2018 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2018

Invited Talks_____

| 2021 | Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations , Samsung Electronics DIT Center | Hwaseong, South Korea |
|------|--|-----------------------|
| 2020 | Learning What and Where to Transfer, Samsung Electronics DIT Center | Hwaseong, South Korea |
| 2019 | Learning What and Where to Transfer, Summer Annual Conference of IEIE | Jeju, South Korea |
| 2018 | Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically, NAVER Labs | Seongnam, South Korea |

Teaching Experience _____

| 2020 | ia: "Semantic Segmentation and Object Detection", Samsung DS Al Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | rongin, South Korea |
|------|--|-----------------------|
| 2019 | TA: "Optimization and Regulaization", SK Hynix ML Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | Daejeon, South Korea |
| 2019 | TA: "Transfer and Multi-task Learning", Samsung DS AI Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | Daejeon, South Korea |
| 2018 | TA, Seongnam-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | Seongnam, South Korea |
| 2018 | TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | Daejeon, South Korea |
| 2017 | TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin) | Seoul, South Korea |